bike24.com 2017-09-01

# Bike24 - Privacy Policy

Bike24 treats the protection of your personal data very seriously. We act strictly in accordance with the statutory provisions of the German Federal Data Protection Act (BSSG) as well as the German Teleservices Act (TMG).

Personal data is information, which can be used to determine your identity. This includes, for instance, your actual name, your address, phone number.

## 1\. Anonymous data collection

In principle you can use our website(s) without revealing your identity. Data is saved for storage and protection purposes, when you access our website(s). The following data is stored:

  * Date, time
  * Type of request, protocol type and access status
  * Size of the file
  * Name of the file
  * Information about the website from which you found us
  * Description of the type of web browser version used and the operating system

This data is only used anonymously for statistical purposes. The data is stored for security reasons to ensure the secure operation of our system.

### The use of cookies

Cookies are small files with configuration information, which we use for technical control purposes. We do not record any personal data using cookies. It is also possible to use our websites without cookies partly. Most browsers are configured in such a way that they automatically accept cookies. You can deactivate the acceptance of cookies by the browser in the browser settings or configure your browser in such a way that it informs you as soon as cookies are sent. You can have the cookies that were accepted by the browser displayed in the browser settings and delete the cookies.

## 2\. Collection of personal data

However, in certain cases we require personal data from you. This is the case:

  * If you place an order
  * If you contact us
  * If you register for personalised services and password protected areas
  * If you register/cease to register for the Bike24 newsletter
  * If you further recommend products
  * If you provide feedback via the feedback form and we should respond to your feedback

If you want to provide feedback via the Bike24 feedback form then you can optionally enter personal data. You can also use the feedback form if you waive the entry of personal data. It is only possible to respond to your feedback if you state your e-mail address.

## 3\. Use and passing on of personal data

We use personal data to process your order, to deliver the goods, to inspect your creditworthiness, for the payment handling, to prevent the misuse of our website and to inform you about your orders, products and offers.

On request you also have the possibility to receive information about your personal data you have stored at Bike24. However, blocking or deletion of personal data is only possible if the statutory retention periods permit this. For further information please contact us by e-mail.

You will, of course, only receive advertising from Bike24 if you have expressly consented to the sending of advertising material. For instance you can register for the Bike24 Newsletter in the course of the ordering process or whilst expressly stating your e-mail address via the separate newsletter page. Of you can, of course, cancel your consent to the sending of advertising material at any time.

### Transfer to third parties

Bike24 shall not illicitly pass on personal data to third parties. In particular Bike24 shall not pass on any personal data to third parties for advertising purposes.

Bike24 passes on personal data to service partners to ensure the optimum processing of your order if this is necessary to complete the order. In this way we transmit data to shipping companies (DHL/Deutsche Post AG, DPD, UPS, forwarders), who will deliver the goods to you. It is also possible that the order will be passed on to a supplier, who will deliver the goods directly to you. The data transmitted may only be used by the recipient to fulfil its task.

In addition we transmit personal data to our service partners relating to the fields of financing, processing of credit card payments, credit assessments as well as the collection of receivables. Data will only be transmitted to service partners in accordance with the provisions of the German Federal Data Protection Act.

The extent to which data is transferred to third parties shall be limited to the necessary minimum levels.

### Feedback data

If you inform us of your e-mail address via the feedback form then we will only use this to respond to your feedback. Feedback data is assessed anonymously and used to improve and optimise our website as well as our processes. No feedback data shall be passed onto third parties.

## 4\. Protection of personal data

If you submit an order to Bike24 or register for a personalised or password protected area, your personal data will be encrypted and protected from access by unauthorised parties when it is transmitted on the internet. Bike24 uses a secure transmission procedure - the so-called "Secure Socket Layer" (SSL) transmission. SSL is a protocol for the encryption of messages on the internet, which offers particularly high levels of security.

## 5\. Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager

This website uses Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager, web analytics services provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States.

In case IP-anonymisation is activated on this website, your IP address will be truncated within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transfered to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-anonymisation is active on this website.

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing them other services relating to website activity and internet usage.

The IP-address, that your Browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics, will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Addon for your current web browser: [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

## 6\. Links to other websites

You will find links to other websites on our websites to keep you really well informed. We do not have any influence upon the design and the content of these external websites.

## 7\. Data protection contact

If you have any questions, suggestions or comment to make about the issue of data protection then please contact Bike24 GmbH's data protection officer: datenschutz at bike24.net
